[engine revs]
[Jerry] This is 1957 BMW 507 Roadster,
in papyrus white with blue leather
interior and the optional hard top.
The body is almost
entirely hand formed of aluminum,
and no two are exactly alike.
So the hard top on this car
wouldn’t fit on any other BMW 507.
It’s got a 3.2 liter all aluminum V8
that makes 150 horsepower,
and a four speed gear box,
front disc brakes,
with a top speed of 136 miles an hour.
This is something that happens
once in a while in the car world,
where a car company
gets a little out of control,
a little excited about making something
better than they ever have before,
and they end up putting too much into it,
too much quality, too much detail.
and they suddenly realize, "There’s no way
we can make a profit on this."
They made about 252 of these
before they came to their senses and went,
"We are losing our ass on this car.
Stop! Stop making them!"
And that’s what’s so wonderful about it.
Here’s a car that shouldn’t even exist,
and yet, here it is.
The car was designed by a German
industrial designer, Albrecht von Goertz.
He seems open to compromise
with a room full of accountants.
The Germans are very interesting.
Sometimes they make things
very serious and heavy-handed,
and then sometimes they’re able to make
things like this, very light and delicate.
That combination of talents
can be very potent automotively,
and also in the acting profession,
which is why it is the perfect car...
Let’s go for a ride.
...for my very gifted, very artistic,
and very precise special guest...
Oh my, God, you’re so perfectly dressed
for the car.
...Mr. Christoph Waltz.
Even though Christoph
is mostly a dramatic actor,
he’s so good at what he does,
there’s almost a humor
that he brings to his performances
particularly in Quentin Tarantino’s
masterpiece,
Inglourious Basterds,
where he plays the most
gleefully possible SS Nazi officer.
[in French]
[Jerry] I’m Jewish, but I love this Nazi.
-Ooh...
-[phone rings]
-Hi, Christoph, it’s Jerry Seinfeld.
-[Christoph] Oh, hello. How are ya?
Right now,
I’m at the Busy Bee Hardware store.
[Jerry] Oh yeah, I know where that is.
I also did a movie about bees.
-Were they busy?
-Christoph, there’s no lazy bees.
I’m Jerry Seinfeld and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
-Hey, Christoph.
-Good morning.
I’m trying
to find something in centimeters.
-Why?
-Why? Because inches don't make sense.
[Jerry] Here in America,
we tried to switch over
to the metric system at one point
but it was hard and
we just got really tired.
-It is tiring.
-Yes.
[inaudible]
[Jerry] You love mechanical things.
I think we did talk one time,
about the fountain pen scene.
When under new management, there’s
always a slight duplication of efforts.
Most of it being a complete waste of time,
but needs to be done nevertheless.
Did it ever not go well
when you were shooting it?
Yeah.
[blows raspberry]
[Christoph] It's just lovely.
You picked exactly the right thing.
You know,
I remember this car from my childhood.
[Jerry] Really? In Austria?
[Christoph]
This I can spend the morning with.
Never mind the engine.
-Yeah.
-But this, this is so beautiful.
Christoph, you’re forgetting
one of the essential parts of this show.
You have to get in the car.
This is such a wonderful speed...
-Uh-huh.
-...to be cruising along.
-It’s so civilized.
-Yes.
[Jerry] Had coffee yet this morning?
-[Christoph] No.
-[Jerry] You like coffee?
-[Christoph] I love coffee.
-[Jerry] Great. Me, too.
-So you’re from Vienna, Austria.
-Yeah.
What’s the difference between
Austrians and Germans?
dancing a waltz and the goose step?
So have you seen any episodes
of this show?
No, I’ve purposely tried to
keep myself innocent.
Okay.
This must all seem very odd.
Well, I understand the basis of this,
which doesn’t make it any less odd.
[woman] You look so dapper!
Thank you.
-[man] Comedians in Cars?
-Yes, sir.
-[man] Great show!
-Thank you, appreciate it.
He’s never even seen it.
Oh! You gotta watch every episode
and catch up!
Have a nice day.
See? You’re on a huge hit show right now.
Make no mistake, I'm fully aware of that.
[Jerry] Now when you played Hans Landa
in Inglourious Basterds,
did you think
there’s something funny about this guy?
He was the most evil character
in the story
but he was having the best time.
And also, he left enough space
for the spectator to make up his mind.
Do I see the funny element or do I see
the superficial horror?
[Jerry] Did you have any hesitation
about doing that part?
[Christoph] No.
You can imagine how many Nazi’s
I’ve been offered in my career.
And I never did a single one.
-Oh, really?
-Never.
Because this character was so complex...
-Right.
-...and so interesting.
[Jerry] I like how good villains
are always very well-mannered.
-The elegance.
-I totally agree.
And you brought a lot of that
to that character.
[Christoph] That’s something in comedians
that I admire, the ease and lightness
with which some of them
can address very intense topics.
Apparently, even,
even crows have a sense of humor.
-Crows do?
-Crows do.
They trick each other
just for the fun of it.
Monkeys do it to.
-Monkeys, I expect that of monkeys.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] We’re going to Torrance,
which is just another couple of exits.
My thought here was that because of your
very eclectic background of nationalities
there was only one place
that could possibly service
all of these difference facets
of your background.
The International House of Pancakes.
[operatic instrumental music playing]
[waitress] Anything to drink?
I’d like a cup of coffee.
I have to show you pictures
of the cafes that I grew up in.
Are they like this?
[chattering]
Not really.
[chuckles]
Are you careful about what you eat?
Would you eat that?
[Christoph] No wonder that health care
is so expensive.
[Jerry] We have to fix all of that
after you eat it.
Don’t worry about the consequences.
You eat what you want, we’ll fix it.
That’s the American way of life.
I don’t know why you’re living here.
I think its a very practical thing.
Its more of a craft than an art.
The art is in the writing.
I can't agree with that,
I think they are both arts.
I've heard Quentin Tarantino say
if he didn't find you,
he could not have made the movie.
I don't believe that.
There are good actors and bad actors.
I think there's appropriate casting
and wrong casting.
So, if you're right for the part,
you will be good.
And, if your wrong,
you can be the best actor in the world,
and you will be bad.
The rest is, is...
showing off.
What is Vienna known for?
Music, architecture.
You know, on the list of cities
with the best quality of life,
Vienna is either number one or number two.
What other city would be up there?
Torrance?
What are the similarities between
Vienna and Torrance?
There is an aspect of hopelessness
in both.
Is anybody funny in Vienna?
Oh yeah.
The comedy scene in Vienna
is very authentic.
Can you give me an example
of a Viennese joke?
They’re not always
"slap your thigh" funny.
-Oh.
-Some of them are seriously depressing.
Well, that's good.
It would just be the dream for me
to go to Vienna with you
and for you to show me
the world of Vienna,
as I have shown you Torrance.
-We should do that.
-I would come there to eat.
-Fine.
-I'm gonna pass on the opera.
-Gonna pass on the architecture.
-Yeah, yeah.
-No, no, no.
-I'm gonna pass on the painting.
-As much as we did today.
-Yeah.
I really just want to joke around
with the Viennese comedians
of which you tell me
that culture is vibrant.
I can make that happen.
[waitress] How many pancakes you want?
But there is one aspect
that kind of encompasses all of these.
-Encompasses.
-Encompasses, thank you.
-If you’re gonna live here...
-You have to say--
-...you gotta talk like we talk.
-Yeah.
-[Christoph] What is this thing?
-[Jerry] Butter.
-I’d love to know what you think of it.
-I think I know already what I think.
I love butter.
[in French]
Maybe you would like to try a crepe.
-Much more European than a pancake.
-I agree.
Do you have one?
-How is that?
-Mmm.
The great thing about this is,
how they can make it look
so different from what it tastes.
Okay, so, I see here
they have a Belgian waffle.
A what?
Now that’s from Belgium.
Did you know that?
You want to try it? [chuckles]
You’re going to try it.
[Jerry] So the American pancake,
the French crepe,
the Belgian waffle.
Do you feel like
you’ve kind of been on a journey?
I was about to ask what I ever did to you.
[Christoph]
This IHOP, is that how you say it?
-"I hop"?
-How else could you say it?
-"I hope"?
-I never knew what it is.
I actually always thought
it was cheap shoes.
Why would you think it’s shoes,
because of the hopping?
I’m starting to get this Viennese humor.
There’s quite a bit to it.
[inaudible]
Thank you very much for this...
eye-opener.
Well, that’s not the only thing
that’s gonna open up.
[inaudible]
Where have I brought you now, Christoph?
Where have I brought you now?
-This feels civilized, doesn’t it?
-I totally agree.
-Cheers.
Thank you.
What a wonderful way to spend the morning.
Now I’m starting to understand
the Viennese life perspective.
This is how we do it.
Very nice.
[Jerry] What are you most often
not happy with?
More or less everything.
Good answer.
[Christoph] Cigars is one of these things
is a little bit like I feel about comedy.
It has to be exquisite to be good.
If it’s any less,
you might as well skip it.
[Jerry] Great line.
So, does everybody in Vienna
have these sensibilities,
these very refined sensibilities?
Everybody, without exception.
-Everybody.
-I can’t tell if you’re joking or not.
-I can’t either.